# ANTOINE HERRMANN

Passionate and proficient physics researcher with interests for analytics and computations. Self-taught developer. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team. Open to exploring new fields and meeting new people. Able to bring an original point of view to the table.



### JOB APPLICATION

- · C++/Python developer
- · Data Scientist/Engineer
- · Consultant

#### CONTACT

antoine67.herrmann@laposte.net

+33 (0)6 95 76 67 41

12 rue des mines, 67220, Triembach-au-Val

@AntoineHerrmannGit

in Antoine Herrmann

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Programming**

Python C++ LaTeX



Languages

French
English
German

### **INTERESTS**

Arts: Piano

Sports : Volleyball, Biking, Gym Culture : History, Economy/Finance

Craft: Mechanics

## **WORK HISTORY**

**6** 08/2021 - 08/2022

♥ University of South Florida, Tampa, FL, US Research Assistant

Performed DFT calculations of the electronic structure of diamond nickel peroxide and spin dynamics simulations on atomic lattices - Managed a team of teaching assistants made of computational and theorists

**1** 02/2020 - 08/2020

Complétude,

Private Lecturer

Strasbourg, FR

Private lectures in math, physics, biology and geology (high school level) - material physics, structures physics, applied mathematics (bachelor level)

**1** 02/2020 - 08/2020

**♀** IPCMS.

Research Intern

Strasbourg, FR

Performed analytic calculations of the temperature-dependence of RKKY interaction and laser-induced spin-orbit coupling corrections in 1D, 2D, 3D

**1** 07/2017 - 08/2017

**♀** Bürkert S.A.S,

R&D Intern

Triembach-au-Val, FR

Optimization of flow-measurement models through non-invasive acoustic pulses

## **EDUCATION**

**1** 09/2018 - 09/2020

University of Strasbourg, Strasbourg, FR
 Master of Science

Magistere of Fundamental Physics : Condensed matter physics and nano-physics

Graduate with honor

Physics: Quantum Mechanics - Nuclear Physics - Atomic Physics - Statistical physics

Maths: Complex Analysis - Non-Ninear Algebra - Differential Equations - Functionnal Expansions

**1** 09/2015 - 09/2018

**♥** University of Strasbourg, Strasbourg, FR Bachelor of Science

Bachelor of Deepen Mathematics and Physics

Math: Linear Algebra - Functional Analysis - Topology - Geometry - Differential Equations

Physics: Classical Mechanics - Optics - Hydrodynamics - Thermodynamics

**12/2022 - 12/2022** 

**♀** Online

Deep Learning - Python Computing: Gradient descent optimization - neuronal networks - pipelines

Python: Numpy - Pandas - Matplotlib - Scikitlearn

## **HONOURS AND AWARDS**

▼ French Physicists Tournament 2019 : Golden medal

#### **GENERAL SKILLS**

Teamwork Scrum Analytical thinking Critical thinking

Problem-solving oriented Continuous learning

Tags must be ordered by hand with newlines to get a nice layout, especially for long tags.